It's 2024. People
are out there making money from social
media, and you're
thinking, "Do you know what?
I would love a world where I could just
post to social
media and make money from it." Now,
I'll be transparent with you.
I do make a bit of money from social
media.
But once I show you how much it is,
I'm also going to tell you why you should
never
truly aim to make money from social media.
I've only posted a couple of times,
but I made about £3,300 from YouTube this
month, and in the last year,
about £62,000. Fucking hell.
That's more than I thought. Jesus Christ,
I've got eight grand from a video.
Eight grand. I didn't even plan it.
This is from Facebook for this week,
3,000 US dollars.
And TikTok,
probably do about 1,000 US dollars a
month, which is nice, but
you should absolutely not want to do that.
I'll explain why.
So the way that the monetization works
with these social media platforms, let's
take YouTube, for example.
If you look at YouTube's annual revenue,
which I'm not
even sure what it is, I'd say about
that many people have Premium,
and this many
people watch with the ads.
Do you have YouTube Premium?
You're missing out.
It's good, mate.
You're going traveling soon.
Download videos offline, no ads.
Such a Gen Z, you know. Now,
the amazing thing that YouTube does with
creators is it realizes, yo,
if we give a massive amount of the
income that we make to creators,
they're going to be happy,
and in some cases they
are. However, for every 1,000 views,
this is from...
I don't even know if this is legit,
but we'll use it for an example,
equals $18,
let's say.
So if you wanted to make a meaningful
amount of money from YouTube,
$18, let's say you wanted to make,
I don't know, $1,800 per month,
you're going to need to then hit 100,000
views.
Now, the hardest thing about this
is getting loads of views on YouTube
is very,
very difficult because it's a very
competitive marketplace,
and for your video to
be of the quality to go viral
and be shown to those audiences,
some things need to
happen. Golden rule number one,
YouTube wants your video to get a billion
views.
The first thing it will do whenever you
post a video or piece of content
is show it
to your red hot fans, the people
that watch anything.
Even if you put a video of your dog up,
they're there cheering. They love it.
Then,
if the red hot fans have a good average
view duration, they sit
through it and watch it the whole way,
suddenly it will go, "Ah, let's show it to
your fans." Maybe people
that don't even subscribe to your channel,
but they've
watched a few videos. Again,
average view duration.
If it's pretty good, good retention,
it's probably going to show it on some
more
people.
Let's say now it goes to a warm audience.
Maybe someone that's watched a few of your
videos, didn't sit through many of the
other ones. Cool. Click-through rate
and average view duration.
How many people that YouTube puts it in
front of it decide to click on it, and how
much of that video do they watch? Now,
if you really want to go viral, YouTube
puts your video in front of cold audiences
only because it performed well in front
of these tiers, and it sees what happens.
If you're getting a good click-through
rate, you've obviously picked a topic or
trend that's very important,
that's doing well, that people care about,
that they
feel compelled to watch,
and average view duration.
But what's interesting here is if
that cold audience watch that video,
then they watch other videos
that you've done.
That gets played into your average view
duration.
That's why if a creator can create a binge
effect, it makes their channel go wild.
But having quality
and banks of quality
and having these tiers that YouTube
understands to put people in front of can
take months.
It can take years,
not just for YouTube to understand you,
but for you to
understand your audience
and everything else that goes with it.
So for you to go truly viral,
to get hundreds of thousands of views,
to make a
living from social media
is incredibly difficult.
So what am I saying?
You should not see views as equating
money, because
Google is going to pay you the least
amount of money possible.
You shouldn't be on social media for
YouTube to pay you.
You should be on social media for you to
pay you. Imagine this, Declan.
If I said,
"I can get 1,000 people out there to watch
a video you've created, and I
give you $18," or would you rather have
that 1,000 people to maybe
potentially be interested in something
you're selling?
Because even you as a PT, qualified PT,
if that 1,000 views got you
50 email addresses,
what would you rather have?
50 email addresses or $18?
50 email addresses.
Cool. Because out of that,
you might then send 20 emails over two
months.
How many of them do you reckon would land
on a landing page or at least
check out your services? How many?
10%.
10%. I like that. Cool.
So let's go 1,000 people, 50 emails, 10%,
five
leads. Then if you had a good product,
let's say online coaching, James Smith
Academy, something amazing of that level,
top quality and way better than everyone
else's. Out of those, even
if you took on one client,
how much does a client pay
you for an hour? You're way too cheap,
by the way.
Probably about 50.
Cool. $50. Cool.
So already you've had a better investment
than that.
Now,
what is the average amount of times a
client sees you a month,
on average?
Four.
Cool.
And I know you haven't been doing it long,
but what is the average duration a
client stays with you?
Six months.
So six months at $200. Each client
is worth to you
$1,200.
So why would you settle for $18 from
YouTube
when that 1,000 views could equate to
$1,200 for you?
This is the big mistake people
are making on social media,
and my golden rule is
this.
I showed you my channel rev from before.
If my business isn't making 10 times what
my channel rev is
making,
there is something wrong with my sales
funnel.
It's nice getting paid from social media
because you can take that money and you
can reinvest it in things. Flights,
travel, accommodation. Cool.
Your bill, actually.
All the money I make from YouTube,
someone's like, "Oh my God,
that's £30,000 a year." I hope you earn
that this year and you just take it
straight from me. But fundamentally,
we need to look at social media as a tool
that
takes people down our sales process
and sales funnel, not a way to get paid.
Because if you're Logan Paul, KSI,
MrBeast, this is great, but
you are not running a production company
that relies on views.
One of the best courses that I've done,
and I reference him all the time, is Ed
from Creator Booth. And do you know what?
I'll put a link to his channel in this
because he's changed my life with all of
this. He had someone in his course.
He made 33,000 US dollars from 800 views
because
those views, although not spectacular,
converted people down his funnel.
And if you don't believe me,
this channel has just over 1,000
subscribers, but the
people that watch this content aren't just
red hot leads.
They're business owners
that care about their business, that
are into
self-development, that
are willing to invest.
Fitness professionals out there know
that creatine is worth it because if they
take it,
they get 7% marginal increases in gains.
For 7% gains, they're willing to take
that every day and put it in their water
bottle because they know the compounding
interest of 7% gains over weeks, months,
and years could be a difference in a bench
press, squat, or their sporting
performance to a massive amount.
And the reason that I'm hitting this
channel, the
smaller one,
so much more than my bigger one
is because yeah, my bigger one pays me
£3,000 a month, but my little channel,
my tiny little 1,000
views a video channel,
is paying me considerably more.
So I need to make an executive decision.
What do I care about more?
Getting paid for views
or getting paid for putting out content
and pushing people
down my funnel so they're more inclined to
do business with me?
This video could bomb.
This video right here might get 500 views,
but
out of that,
50 of them might go to the link in the
description and get my 30
days of free business information
that will change your life over 30 days
that's
completely free, sent by email.
And out of that amount of people,
some people will
join the course,
which equates for thousands of dollars for
me to
take on business class. Wee. Not cheap.
Just joking. First class.
Actually, look, first class,
not worth the hype if you ask me.
The step up from economy to business,
great.
But when you go to first class,
especially with an airline like Etihad,
Etihad,
they give you a bed and a seat,
and it's a con because the bed
is way too much of a bed to be a seat,
and the seat is way too much of a seat to
be
a bed. Whereas in business,
you can get that 45-degree recline on.
You can watch TV whilst in bed.
In first class,
although you get a shower and a
butler that has an exquisite wine menu,
sometimes you're like, "Oh, do I want to
lay down?
Do I want to sit up?" Business class,
although you don't get the shower,
which is only for five minutes in first
class, you can still shower at the airport
as you transit through with the Emirates
and whatnot. Where were we?
Ask yourself,
do you want to get paid for views
or do you want to get clients?
Do you want to get paid for views
Because a lot of people out there get
caught up in a battle of just trying to go
viral. Because I've done this before.
I've wasted years of my life just trying
to go viral.
And you get an audience of people
that just liked your video.
They don't like you.
They're not going to use your business,
and that's one of the
traps you shouldn't fall into. Smaller,
niche-er, red hot, get paid by
people, not social media.
Because shit's expensive. Shit
is expensive.
And wouldn't it be nice to live in a world
like this?
So how do you get paid by social media?
You don't.
You pay yourself using social media.
Wing Chun. Aikido.